Processes, Pipes & Redirection Module 3
Learning objectives Stop foreground jobs with Ctrl+C Redirect stdout/stderr to log files Chain commands with pipes Search simulator logs with grep
Prerequisites Module 2 (permissions, executable scripts)
Learning path
Course context Save build/sim output: command > run.log 2>&1 Filter errors: grep -i error run.log Exit status $? indicates success or failure
Core topics
Self-check Watch the terminal demonstration on screen.
Capture full log The following command is shown on screen.
Searching logs Watch the terminal demonstration on screen.
Redirection demo Watch the terminal demonstration on screen.
Practice
Exercise scaffold The following command is shown on screen.
Exercises grep ERROR on ~/unix_practice/sample.log Try 2>&1 | tee debug.log Check echo $? after a command
Summary & next steps Processes and exit status Redirection and pipes Next: Module 4 — shell scripting Next: Module 4: Shell Productivity & Basic Scripting